Now that we have If-statements and loops, the problems that
الان لدينا جمل الشرط والتكرار الشكلة التي
we are going to tackle are going to get more complicated.
سنواجهها أن الأمور ستزداد تعقيدا
Our function bodies are going to get longer as
بنية الدالة ستزداد طولا
well, and are going to need some English explanation.
وسنحتاج بعض الشرح بالإنجليزية
Here is the up_to_vowel function from the While Loop lecture.
هنا الدالةup_to_vowelمن محاضرة الـwhile_loop
We have added two comments.
لقد أضفنا تعليقين
A comment begins with a number sign character.
التعليق يبدأ بعلامة رقم
Often called the hash character.
عادة تسمي هاش
And goes until the end of the line. Python ignores these characters.
ةيستمر التعليق حتي نهاية السطر ويتجاهل البايثون تلك الحروف
Their purpose is to document code, much like doc strings document functions.
والغرض هو توثيق الكود كما أن نصوص الوثيقة توثق الدوال
The first one describes the variables that are used in this function.
الأول يصف المتغيرات المستخدمة في الدالة
Notice how it links together before a vowel s and i.
لاحظ كيف ترتبط ببعضها قبل قبل الحروف المتحركة s و I
Let's explore a little bit about what that means.
دعنا نستكشف قليلاً عن معنى ذلك.
we'll do that using the word zymurgy with indices
سوف نقوم بذلك باستخدام الكلمة zymurgy مع الفهارس
zero,one,two,three,four,five, and six.
صفر، واحد ،أثنان،ثلاثة،أربعة،خمسةو ستة
Well, we know that second index is not
حسناً، نحن نعلم بأن الفهرس الثاني غير
included in my sub-string, so that means that
مضمن في سلسلتي النصية الفرعية، إذا هذا يعني
this is s starting an index zero going up to index seven.
أن الحرف s يبدأ بالفهرس صفر ويزداد حتى الفهرس سبعة.
What is s from zero up through index six?
ما هي قيمة s من الصفر حتى الفهرس ستة؟
That is zymurg.
إنها zymurg.
And it's from zero to five is
ومن الصفر حتى خمسة هي
zymur. S from zero to four
zymur. قيمة s من صفر إلى أربعة هي
is zymu. S from zero to three
zymu. قيمة s من صفر إلى ثلاثة هي
is zym. S from zero to two is zy.
zym. قيمة s من صفر إلى اثنين هي zy.
S from zero to one is z. And here's the fun bit s from
قيمة s من صفر إلى واحد هي z. وهنا المرح قليلاً قيمة s من
zero to zero, just following this pattern of reducing
صفر إلى صفر، باتباع هذا النمط من إنقاص
the length by one gives me just the empty string.
الطول بمقدار واحد يعطيني سلسلة نصية فارغة.
Well, we start before vowel off at the empty string and I starts off at zero.
حسناً، لنبدأ من قبل الحرف الصوتي في السلسلة النصية الفارغة وسأبدأ من الصفر.
So if we plug zero in
وبالتالي إذا حشرنا صفر في
[INAUDIBLE]
[كلام غير مسموع]
I, we end up at from, with a S from zero to zero, that's this.
سوف أخلص إلى منه، مع s من الصفر، هذه هي.
And S from zero through zero is the
وقيمة s من الصفر إلى صفر هي
empty string, so indeed, before vowel contains all
السلسلة النصية الفارغة، إذاً بالفعل قبل الحرف الصوتي يحتوي كافة المحارف
the characters found in S from zero through
التي وجدت في s من صفر حتى
zero and before vowel is the empty string.
صفر وقبل الحرف الصوتي سلسلة نصية فارغة.
This simple initialization, where we assign an empty
هذه التهيئة البسيطة حيث قمنا بإسناد سلسلة نصية فارغة
string to before value and we assign zero
قبل القيمة وإسنادنا للقيمة صفر
to i.
إلى المتحول i.
Establishes that this description here is correct.
تبرهن أن هذا التوصيف هنا صحيح.
Furthermore, the first time through the loop we're going to add s at index zero to
بل أكثر من ذلك، في أول مرة في الحلقة سوف نقوم بإضافة s عند الفهرس صفر
before vowel and replace what we had. Well now before vowel contains a Z.
إلى ما قبل الحرف الصوتي واستبدال ما لدينا. حسناً الآن قبل الحرف الصوتي يوجد الحرف Z.
I was zero, so i plus 1 is 1, will make i 1.
لقد كنت عند الصفر، لذلك i زائد 1 تعطينا 1.
Now we're on that row when i is 1. And indeed this
الآن نحن عند ذلك السطر حيث قيمة i هي 1. وبالفعل
description still is true.
لا يزال هذا التوصيف صحيحاً.
The next time through the loop we look at
إذا نظرنا في المرة الأخرى عبر الحلقة
S at index one, coming up here that's the y.
عندما s عند الفهرس واحد، يأتينا هنا الحرف y.
We take the y and we tack it on to the end of before vowel, and then we increment i.
نأخذ y ونتتبعها إلى النهاية قبل الحرف الصوتي، ومن ثم نزيد قيمة i.
I is now two, so S, from zero through
إنها اثنان الآن وبالتالي قيمة s من الصفر إلى
two is indeed what we have saved inside before vowel.
اثنين هي بالفعل ما حفظناه بالداخل قبل الحرف الصوتي.
Maintaining this sort of relationship between variables
المحافظة على هذا النوع من العلاقة بين المتحولات
is a bit of a tricky business, but it
هو نوع من العمل الشاق لكنه
really helps to understand what's going on inside this loop.
يساعدنا حقاً على فهم ما يجري داخل الحلقة.
Coming up with these relationships in the first place is
الخروج بهذه العلاقات هو في المقام الأول
also challenging but with practice you'll get better and better.
تحد أيضاً لكن بالتدريب ستصبح أفضل فأفضل.
Whenever you write a loop there's going to be a relationship between your variables.
كلما كتبت حلقة سيكون هناك علاقة بين متحولاتك.
Try and figure out what that relationship is and
حاول اكتشاف تلك العلاقة
you'll have an easier time writing your loop body.
وسوف يكون لديك وقتاً أسهل لكتابة جسم الحلقة.
Also, once you figure out that relationship, write it down.
أيضاً، حالما تكتشف العلاقة قم بكتابتها.
Put it in a comment so that you don't have to
ضعها في تعليق وبالتالي لن يكون عليك
figure it out again the next time you read the code.
اكتشافها مرة أخرى عندما تقرأ الكود في المرة التالية.
This second comment, accumulate the non-vowels at the beginning of the string,
هذا التعليق الثاني، يراكم الأحرف غير الصوتية في بداية السلسلة النصية.
describes what the loop does, much like doc strings don't say how functions work.
يصف ما تقوم به الحلقة، كما لو أنه نص توثيق ولا يقول كيف تعمل الدالة.
This comment does not say how this loop gets the job done.
هذا التعليق لا يقول كيف تقوم الحلقة بإنجاز العمل.
It just describes the effect.
إنه يصف النتيجة فقط.
Comments are intended for programmers and so they don't
التعليقات موجهة للمبرمجين وبالتالي هم
need to describe how the loop does its job.
ليسوا بحاجة لوصف كيفية إنجاز الحلقة للعمل.
You should try and comment complicated bits of code to explain.
عليك أن تحاول وتقوم بالتعليق على الأجزاء المعقدة من الكود للشرح.
The purpose of it.
الغرض منها.
And you should also write comments
وعليك أيضاً كتابة التعليقات
to describe relationships between your variables.
لوصف العلاقة بين متحولاتك.